Here, I'll step through the code for
ここでは シンプル mover ノードのコードを実施して
the simple mover node and explain what's happening at each step of the way.
各ステップで何が起こっているのかを説明します
Rospy is the official Python client library for ROS.
Rospy は ROS 向けの公式 Python クライアントライブラリです
It provides most of the fundamental functionality
Python と ROS を連動させる上で
required for interfacing with ROS via Python.
必要な基本的機能のほとんどが備わっています
It has tools for creating nodes interfacing with topics,
トピックやサービス パラメーターなどと連動して
services, parameters, and more.
ノードを作成するインターフェースも含まれています
It will certainly be worth your time to check out
詳細は Rospy API ドキュメンテーションと下記のリンクを
the Rospy API documentation and the links below.
ぜひ参照してください
General information about rospy,
Rospy に関する一般的な情報とその他のチュートリアルは
including other tutorials may be found on the ROS wiki.
ROS Wiki で確認できます
First off, from the standard messages package,
まず初めに 標準メッセージパッケージから
we import Float64, which is one of the primitive message types in ROS.
ROSの主要なメッセージタイプの一つであるFloat64をインポートしてます
This package also contains all of the other primitive types.
このパッケージには他の全ての主要なタイプも含まれます
Later on in this script,
このスクリプトでは後ほど
we will be publishing a Float64 message to the position command topics for each joint.
Float64 メッセージを各ジョイントの位置コマンドトピックにパブリッシュします
At the top of the mover function,
mover 関数の先頭で
two publishers are declared.
2 つのパブリッシャーが宣言されています
One for joint one commands,
1 つは joint_1 についての
and one for joint two commands.
もう 1 つは jouint_2 についてのコマンドです
Here, the queue size parameter is used to determine the maximum number of
ここで queue_size パラメーターは メッセージが削除される前に
messages that may be stored in the publisher before messages are dropped.
パブリッシャーに格納される最大メッセージ数を決定するために使用されます
More information about this parameter can be found in the links below.
このパラメーターに関する詳細は 以下のリンクを参照してください
Here, I'm initializing a client node and registering it with the master.
ここでクライアントノードを初期化して マスターに登録します
Our mover is the name of the node,
ここでの arm_mover はノードの名前です
and the init node function must be called before
他の Rospy パッケージ関数が呼び出される前に
any other Rospy package functions are called.
init_node 関数を呼び出す必要があります
On line 13, the rate object is created.
13 行でレートオブジェクトが作成されます
And here, we set it with a value of 10 hertz.
ここでオブジェクトは 10 ヘルツ の値に設定します
Rates are used to limit the frequency at which certain loops spin in ROS.
このレートはROSで特定のループが回る頻度を制限するために使用されます
Choosing a rate which is too high may result in unnecessarily high CPU usage,
レートが高すぎると CPU 使用率が不必要に高くなり
while choosing a rate that's too low could result in high overall system latency.
レートが低すぎるとシステム全体に遅延が生じる可能性があります
Choosing sensible values for all of the nodes in a ROS system is a bit of a fine art.
ROS システムのすべてのノードで適度な値を選択するには 高度な技術が必要です
Start time is used to determine how much time has elapsed.
start_time は経過時間を特定するために使用します
When using ROS with simulated time,
ここで行っているように
as we're doing here,
シミュレーション時間で ROS を使用している場合
rospy.time.now will initially return
rospy.time.now はクロックトピックで最初のメッセージが受信されるまで
zero until the first message has been received on the clock topic.
最初は 0 を返します
This is why start time is set and pulled continuously until a non-zero value is returned.
このためスタート時間を設定し 0 以外の値が返されるまで定期的にポーリングを行います
Here, we have the main loop due to the call to rate.sleep,
ここでは rate.sleep を呼び出すためメインループがあります
the loop is traversed at approximately 10 hertz.
ループはおよそ 10 ヘルツでスキャンします
Each trip through the body of the loop will result
ループの本体を走査するたびに
in two joint command messages being published.
2 つのジョイントコマンドメッセージがパブリッシュされます
The joint angles are sampled from a sine wave with a period of 10 seconds
ジョイント角はマイナス 2 分のパイからプラス 2 分のパイまでの間の
and in magnitude from negative pi over two to positive pi over two.
正弦波から 10 秒周期でサンプリングされます
When the node receives the signal to shut down,
ノードがシャットダウンシグナルを
either from the master,
マスターから
or via SIGINT via the console window,
またはコンソールウィンドウの SIGINT シグナルを介して受信すると
the loop will be exited and the program will continue.
ノードは終了しプログラムが継続します
Here, if the name variable is set to main
name 変数を main に設定すると
indicating that this script is being executed directly,
このスクリプトを直接実行し
the mover function will be called.
mover 関数を呼び出します
The try-except blocks here are significant as Rospy uses exceptions extensively.
Rospy は例外を広く使用するため この try-except ブロックは重要な役割を担っています
The particular exception being caught here is the ROS interrupt exception.
ここで ROS  interrupt exception という例外がキャッチされています
This exception is raised when the node has been signaled for shut down.
この例外は ノードにシャットダウンシグナルが送信された場合に発生します
If there was perhaps some sort of cleanup needing to be done
ノードをシャットダウンする前に何らかのクリーンアップが必要な場合は
before the node shuts down, it would be done here.
ここで実行します
More information about Rospy exceptions can be found in the links below.
Rospy 例外に関する詳細は 以下のリンクを参照してください
Assuming that your work space has recently been
ワークスペースを最近構築して
built and it's setup.bash has been sourced,
setup.bash をソースしている場合には
you can launch simple arm as follows.
以下のようにシンプルアームを起動することができます
Once the ROS master,
ROS マスターと Gazebo
gazebo and all of our relevant nodes are up and running,
すべての関連ノードが立ち上がり実行されると
we can finally launch the simple mover node.
シンプル mover ノードが起動できます
All right,
はい
and here's what it should look like.
このようになります
Congratulations. You've now written your first ROS node.
お疲れさまでしたこれで 1 つ目の ROS ノードの記述が完了しました